I'm going to show you how to make a video. I'm going to show you how to make a video.
I'm going to show you how to make video. I'm going to show you how to make video.
Well, good morning, Canvas Community Church. If you are watching this, it is because we had to cancel services due to winter weather, which for some of you might be really exciting.
For others of you might be really frustrating, probably depends on how long your driveway is, how many sidewalks you have to shovel.
But we are so glad that you could join us for a pulled back online service.
We wanted to make sure that we had something together so that we could still gather together and stay on schedule with our sermon series.
This first Sunday in January for me, I always like to do a recap of our mission, vision and values, talk about where we're at as a church, where we're headed as a church.
I did not want to miss that opportunity this morning. So I'm glad that you could join us.
If you haven't met me yet, my name is Ryan. I have the privilege of being one of the pastors here at Canvas Community Church.
Let me cover a few announcements. And then Donovan has recorded a couple of acoustic worship songs for us to prepare our hearts and our minds.
And then I'll come back and I will share kind of a vision series for a vision sermon for 2024 covering our mission, vision values.
I will try and keep it concise. I hope we'll see how that goes.
So announcements. Passages classes were supposed to start this Sunday.
We have two, one before service, one after service.
They will be starting next week on the 14th.
The one before service is on the Sermon on the Mount.
And that's a great class. We'd love for you to check that out.
You can sign up on the website or through the email newsletter.
The other one is starting point. That is for those of you that might be new to the faith, newer to the faith, coming back to the faith for the first time in a long time really covers the foundations of following Jesus.
It's a great way to kind of jumpstart your faith journey.
And Jamie Jackson is going to be leading that.
Also, we were supposed to have a youth night tonight, which if we cancel church, we're not having the youth night.
All right. So the makeup date for that is going to be two Sundays from now on the 21st at 530 p.m.
That will be Donovan's first kind of event as our new youth pastor, which we are so excited about.
And so we'd love for all of our middle school, high school students and their parents to join them.
There's going to be food. You're going to come together, do some fun activities.
Then we're going to split apart. Donovan is going to talk to the parents.
Some of the youth staff is going to hang out with the students. So that's going to be a great thing.
Love to have you join us on the 21st.
Lastly, on the 21st, we are launching our new cycle of small groups.
Small groups are so important to me. They have literally transformed my life.
I am who I am as a person and as a follower of Jesus because of some of the relationships I have built through small groups.
I believe in them with all of my being. And so I would love for you to experience that.
This is a ministry that's been growing at our church last year when we launched.
I think we had three or four small groups this year. We have 10 launching.
There are new groups that are wide open for those of you that haven't been a part of a group at all.
I'd love for you to join a small group.
We have a couple of cool creative small groups this cycle.
There's one that's on Wednesday morning at 10 at the church.
That's kind of targeted at stay at home parents and that kind of demographic that maybe it's hard to get to a night group because of bedtimes or other evening activities.
We'd love for you to check that out. I think there's a Tuesday morning and a Friday morning group that are both led by retired people.
And so that's another unique time slot for people that evenings might be difficult or challenging for.
It's not none. None of those groups are limited to that demographic.
But I think, you know, if you're in that demographic, those three groups would be great groups for you.
There's a brand new group launching on Sunday night. Well, no, Sunday.
It's kind of late afternoon, 430, I believe.
And that's another great family small group.
If you've got kids that have early bedtimes, that's going to be at Ben and Caroline Evers.
I'd love for you to check that out.
I think another brand new family style group is launching on Thursday nights.
And so I'd love for you to just check out all the groups on the website.
Look at your schedule, see what fits best for you.
I would love to see more of our people get plugged into small groups, experience real Christ centered community that literally can have the power to transform your life.
Often we don't realize how much we need community until things go bad in our lives.
And so don't wait for something to go bad to find your people, find your people now.
They will, I promise, help you carry through with prayer and and with support in the most difficult times of your life.
So I think that's all I have for now.
Really excited about this upcoming year, about what I believe that God has in store for us as a church.
Thanks so much for joining us. Let me pray.
Donovan has two songs for us to prepare our minds and hearts for the Scriptures.
I'll come back and give a vision sermon for 2024.
And then we really cannot wait to get back together in person next Sunday.
Father, we are so grateful.
We're so grateful for technology that allows us to gather together in a unique way, even when the weather is not allowing us to get together in person.
I'm thankful for all of the people that invest time and energy into making technology like this possible and accessible.
God, I am so grateful that you have allowed us to be together as a church, that you've called us on mission together.
I'm so thankful for each and every person that calls Canvas their church.
May 2024 be a year where we walk in obedience with you, where you transform us into your image.
You conform us to the image of Jesus so that we can be the hands and feet of Jesus to the watching world.
May the city of Winchester have the kingdom of God more visible this year because we walked in obedience.
May your kingdom come.
May your will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Next Sunday is going to be a fundamental message on kind of what we believe about discipleship as a church.
It's going to lead us into an eight week series on prayer and fasting.
All of our small groups or at least most of them are going to be centered around this teaching on prayer and fasting.
So I can't wait for that to happen.
Excited for you to be a part of that.
And so let's pray and we will hop into the Scriptures and I will try and be concise.
Father, lead us by your Holy Spirit this morning.
May you be present in each room that everyone is gathered in as they watch or listen to this message.
May your Holy Spirit challenge us, encourage us and point us to you.
God, may we be a people who rely on your word, who obey your word together in community with one another.
It's in Jesus name I pray. Amen.
So a few years back, my wife and her mother planned a trip to go to a women's retreat together.
And a couple of weeks before this women's retreat, my mother in law had bought a brand new vehicle.
It was the first like new vehicle that she had in a long time.
It had all of the bells and whistles and screens and technology.
And so she had planned to come pick Marissa up and they were going to drive together to the women's retreat.
And a couple hours before she was supposed to pick Marissa up, she called me and she was in a panic.
And the reason that she was in a panic is because she had driven two hours in the wrong direction.
Now, how did she drive two hours in the wrong direction?
Well, she drove two hours in the wrong direction because she had this new navigation system in her car.
She thought she had put in the coordinates.
And so when she left the house, she knew the way to go for the first hour or two hours.
And so she she was headed in the right direction for a while.
And then what happened is she looked down and she started to follow the red line of her navigation system, which essentially the red line is just following the direction that she's headed.
So she gets on the highway headed in the wrong direction.
But because she had thought that she'd put the navigation system in, she just kept looking down and she's like, I guess I'm going in the right direction.
And it took her a few hours to realize the mistake that had been made.
And the reason I share this story at the beginning of our message is because if we're not careful, it's really easy to drift from your intended direction.
Oftentimes we get started in a direction.
We feel comfortable.
We know where we're headed.
But if we don't keep a close eye on the direction that we're headed, we can easily drift.
And last week, Matt asked us to consider this question.
He said, what is it that you want in your relationship with Jesus in 2024?
And what do you need to focus on to get there?
What direction are you headed?
And what do you need to do to ensure that you get to the direction that you hope to get to?
This week, I want to take that question.
I want to expand it from the individual level to the church level.
See, when we sat down to create our mission, vision and values, essentially what we did is we answered this question that Matt asked last week.
Where do you want to go?
Where, what are you hoping to get out of your, what are we hoping to get out of our church moving forward?
Our mission, vision and values is essentially the answer to that question.
Where do we want to go?
And as we seek to follow Jesus together in this specific local church, this is where we want to go.
I said this last time I shared the mission, vision, values, but my belief is that every New Testament, Bible believing, Jesus loving church essentially has the same mission, vision and values.
Our mission is the Great Commission to go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them and discipling them, teaching them to obey Jesus.
Our values, our values are the New Testament ethics, all, almost every good Bible believing, Jesus centered church.
We all have the same mission and values.
However, each local church has a unique calling, just like individuals in the body have unique callings and spiritual gifts.
I believe each local church has a unique calling, a specific gift, a purpose that they get to play in their city for this time in history that they exist.
And so, yes, we're all about making disciples, baptizing, teaching our values are the values of the New Testament, but our written mission, vision values is kind of our attempt to focus.
What is it unique to us?
What is specific to our church that we feel called to do?
And the reality is this, there's no perfect church.
There are, you're never going to find a church that completely aligns with everything that you value.
We are by no means a perfect church.
But this mission, vision, value statement is our best attempt, our best effort to say together, this is where we're headed.
This is where we want to go as a church.
And so I'd love for you to consider these things.
I want you to love our church.
I want you to commit to our church and be a part of this thing together.
But as we share, if there are things that you're concerned about or don't like or all or just like, man, I don't know that I would that I'm super pumped about that thing.
Man, this is what we're doing as a church.
And like we could use the space.
So like I'm not asking you to leave, but like don't try and take our church and make it your church.
Like this is our church.
This is where we're headed together.
Let's do this thing together.
I asked you to consider, is this a church that you're willing to commit to?
I had a conversation with some people the other day that were talking about whether or not they wanted to become members.
And they were like, man, like we know membership is the serious investment.
And so we just want to take our time to make sure that this really is the church we want to plug into.
I want that for all of you, because there's plenty of great churches in our city.
I am friends with many pastors in our city that have wonderful churches.
And so my goal here is not to say that our church is the right church, the best church.
This is just who we are.
We want you to be a part of it.
We're excited about it.
I personally love our church.
I would go to our church if you all didn't pay me to go to our church.
But it's not for everyone.
And so I might share some things today that you didn't know about our church or that make you uncomfortable.
That's OK.
Let's talk.
My goal is not to grow our church, but to see God's kingdom grow on earth as it is in heaven.
OK, so the rest of our time, mission, vision, values.
And ultimately, I want to ask the question, how are we doing as a church?
And I want you to think, how am I individually living into this mission, this vision, this values?
So our mission, why do we exist?
What do we want to see happen as a church?
We exist to invite real people with real lives into a Christ-centered community.
If you ask me, this is a pretty catchy marketing phrase.
If I do say so myself, I was a part of helping create it.
So that's maybe a little bit self-centered.
But what does it actually mean, right?
Like, what do we mean when we say this thing?
And really, there's two parts to our mission statement.
The first part is Christ-centered community.
In order for us to have some place to invite people, we first have to be creating a Christ-centered community.
The church exists to be the body of Christ to the world.
There's nothing worth inviting the world to if we aren't embodying the life-transforming power of the gospel together.
So first and foremost, if we are going to be successful as a church at doing the thing we say we want to do,
at going the direction we say we want to go, we have to be creating a Christ-centered community.
I love how St. Teresa of Avila says it.
She says, "Christ has no body, no body now but ours.
Go and be Christ's body to the world."
This is what we want as a church.
We want to create a Christ-centered community.
A body of believers that embody the presence and power of the gospel of Jesus.
Oftentimes the way we've preached the gospel in America, my opinion here,
it's so individualized that we've detached salvation from the body of Christ.
The reality is the gospel doesn't just reconcile us back to God, but it reconciles us back to one another
so that we can embody the message of the gospel of Jesus.
At Canvas, our top priority is that those who follow Jesus would pursue genuine, authentic community together.
That our lives and our relationships would embody the abundant life that Jesus has invited us into.
I want our church to be an oasis of sacrificial, unconditional love, forgiveness, and acceptance in a world that's desperate for it.
So what does this look like?
I want to reread a passage in Romans chapter 12 that, in my opinion, is probably the clearest explanation for what I think a Christ-centered community looks like.
And if you will, just close your eyes as I read this passage or look at the words on the screen or whatever,
and focus in and just think like, man, what would it be like to be a part of a community like this?
And what might forming a community like this, what impact might it have on our city?
Romans 12:9 says, "Let love be without hypocrisy.
Hate evil.
Cling to what is good.
Love one another deeply as brothers and sisters.
Take the lead in honoring one another.
Do not lack diligence and zeal.
Be fervent in the Spirit.
Serve the Lord.
Rejoice in hope.
Be patient in affliction.
Be persistent in prayer.
Share with the saints in their needs.
Pursue hospitality.
Bless those who persecute you.
Bless and do not curse.
Rejoice with those who rejoice.
Weep with those who weep.
Live in harmony with one another.
Do not be proud.
Instead, associate with the humble.
Do not be wise in your own estimation.
Do not repay evil for evil.
But give careful thoughts to do what is honorable in everyone's eyes.
And if possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone."
Wow.
I don't know about you, but I want to be a part of a community that embodies these truths.
And I believe that if we're going to do that, it starts with all of us as individuals focusing on Christ, cultivating a community that is centered around Christ.
So, how are we doing at creating a Christ-centered community?
Do our interactions with one another model the love of Jesus?
Do our conversations in the lobby, at small group, team huddles, membership meetings, do they reflect the truths we just read in the Scripture?
This type of community, it's only possible when each of us as individuals pursue Christ with our whole mind and our whole heart, with all of our strength.
Does that describe you?
Does that describe me?
If we want to create a Christ-centered community, it starts with each and every one of us pursuing Christ together and then pursuing Christ in community.
And all of that, the goal of all of that is so that we can invite people into that Christ-centered community.
We believe that Christ is the power of God for life and salvation.
We want our friends, our coworkers, our family members, our neighbors, and yes, even our enemies to experience this transforming power.
So, we intentionally invite people into our community so that they can explore the message of Jesus in a safe and welcoming environment.
The reality is for a long time in America, whether intentionally or unintentionally, churches kind of created this environment where people felt like they had to kind of fake it in order to feel welcome at church.
They had to come in, they had to put their best foot forward, they had to dress up in all of the nice clothes, they had to know all of the lingo, or at least pretend to know all of the lingo.
And the reality is at Canvas, like, we don't want that to be true.
We want to be a safe place for people who don't know Jesus, for people who are coming back to Jesus for the first time in a long time, for people who have no biblical knowledge whatsoever.
We want it to be a safe place for them to explore faith, to come into our Christ-centered community and see why the message of Jesus is so powerful, both for eternal salvation and for abundant life now.
Jesus says this to those who would make it hard for people to feel welcome and follow Jesus.
In Matthew chapter 23, he says,
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You are like whitewashed tombs, which look beautiful on the outside, but inside are full of bones of the dead and everything unclean.
In the same way, on the outside you appear to people as righteous, but on the inside you are full of hypocrisy and wickedness."
At Canvas, our goal is to create a safe place for real people with real lives to explore faith.
We want people to know that Jesus loves them as they are, and so do we.
But he loves them too much to stay there.
We want people to know that we know how flawed we are. We know how broken we are.
We are not trying to create some persona that we are amazing people.
We are broken in need of God's grace.
And we want this to be a safe place.
I had a conversation with somebody a couple Sundays ago.
It was just one of those in passing, "Hey, how are you doing?"
And this person said, "Well, you know, not really great."
And I was like, "Hmm, great, cool."
So I stopped and just kind of was like, "Okay, well, like, help me understand what's going on."
He's like, "Man, we're talking about all this stuff: hope, love, joy, peace."
He's like, "If I'm honest, it's really hard for me to really experience any of that right now."
And that was one of the most refreshing conversations I've had at church in forever.
And then a couple of guys that are friends with him heard, overheard the conversation we were having.
They swooped in and they said, "Dude, let's go to lunch. Let's have a conversation.
Like, don't go through this alone."
That is what we mean when we say that we exist to invite real people with real lives into a Christ-centered community.
Are we becoming together a people of love who invite real people with real lives into a safe place to explore faith?
Are we ourselves? Are we honest with ourselves? Are we honest with others about who we actually are?
Are we creating a nonjudgmental and kind environment for those searching for God?
We exist to become like Christ together, to invite our friends, family, co-workers, and even our enemies
to experience the love and abundant life that comes from following Jesus.
We pray for them. We invite them.
For the longest time, I was intimidated by this passage in Scriptures where Paul says, "Follow me as I follow Christ."
I don't know about you, but that's a heavy statement to come out of anyone's mouth.
But the more I think about it, the more I realize that I think that really is the call of discipleship for every follower of Jesus.
May we be able to say, "Look, I'm doing my best to follow Jesus.
Why don't you follow me as I follow Jesus?"
We'll follow Jesus together.
Okay, so that's our mission statement.
And our vision statement is how do we measure success?
How do we know if we are doing this well?
Our vision statement is this: to cultivate the kingdom of God on earth by proclaiming Jesus clearly and obeying Jesus boldly.
Again, another two-parter, so let's break it down first.
Success for us looks like cultivating God's kingdom.
Our desire as a church is that we would play a small part in making God's kingdom more visible on earth as it is in heaven.
This is what Jesus tells us to pray for: pray that God's kingdom would come, that his will would be done on earth as it is in heaven.
We pray for that, and we seek to be a part of that happening in some small way.
We're more concerned with building the brand of Jesus than our own.
We want to see God's kingdom built.
If our church grows, great, but that's not our ultimate goal.
Our ultimate goal is that the name of Jesus would be made famous in our city.
The reality is our church has been experiencing consistent growth for the past few months.
Our highest attendance Sunday was a few weeks ago.
There was 120 people more in this building than the first Sunday we met a little over a year ago.
That's amazing. We're so thankful for that. We're excited about that.
And with this type of growth, many churches in our situation would be having conversations about growth and expansion,
about how do we create more services? How do we raise money to buy a bigger building?
What do we do to accommodate this growth?
And although none of those things are bad, the conversations that we've been having as a leadership team at Canvas is more about multiplication.
Because our vision isn't about growing our church. Our vision is about cultivating the kingdom of God in our city and on earth.
And so we've been having conversations about how can we use the growth that we're having and leverage it to plant churches,
to revitalize struggling churches, to strategically partner with other churches so that the kingdom of God can be made more visible in our city.
There are all kinds of churches around our area that are chasing after this together.
We're part of a pastor's prayer lunch where 12 to 15 pastors of other local churches.
We get together. We pray for one another. We partner with one another.
There's a sense that the kingdom of God, that we are together as churches.
Our women's retreat, I was talking to Jill last week.
She said that we had 32 women at our women's retreat from eight different churches.
This is success. This is what success looks like.
We want to see the kingdom of God cultivated in our city.
It's not about growing our church.
There's value in churches of every size.
Larger churches in our area have ministries and resources that allow them to do incredible things for the kingdom of God.
We are so thankful for these big churches in our city.
We love them and we partner with them.
However, we believe that that churches our size and smaller also bring a really strategic and important value to the kingdom.
And so we've just talked about, man, what would it look like instead of trying to become bigger and bigger and bigger?
What would it look like if we were a kingdom hub in our city that was sending people out to plant churches, sending people out to struggling churches to revitalize?
The reality is our church is a result of creative partnerships and revitalization.
We are a church that was a merger of two churches.
It was a creative kingdom partnership.
As we look to the future, we just want to say, what if that is our legacy in this city?
What if our legacy is to creatively build relationships with other churches, to plant churches, to revitalize churches and to make strategic partnerships happen so that the kingdom of God can be more visible in our city?
That happens by the second part of our vision statement by proclaiming Jesus clearly and obeying Jesus boldly.
The gospel was, is, and will always be good news for the poor, opening the eyes of the blind and setting captives free.
The message of the gospel should never be void of tangible expressions of love to the marginalized and hurting in our community.
It's not just preach.
It's not just obey.
It's preach and obey.
Serve, love, share.
This is literally, it's literally the only thing the early church could find common ground on.
Peter and Paul, they were getting together to talk about Jews and Gentiles and how the whole early church was going to work.
And they were struggling to agree on just about anything.
But they finally were able to find unity.
And when they left in the midst of their unity, Paul says this in Galatians 2:10.
He said, "All they asked was that we should continue to remember the poor, the very thing I have been eager to do all along."
If we can't agree on anything else as a church, may we agree on obeying Jesus and proclaiming Jesus.
The gospel is to be both preached and lived, both heard and experienced.
How are we doing at this balance?
How are we proclaiming the message of Jesus with our words and obeying the message of Jesus with our lives?
I believe the more we genuinely and humbly proclaim the message of Jesus with our words and our actions,
the more we will see glimpses of God's kingdom on earth as it is in heaven.
Okay, I think I'm, I don't know how I'm doing on time.
I don't think I'm doing great.
So I'm going to try and push through these core values.
The reality of this is that mission and vision that I just gave you is massive.
We could spend the rest of our lives chasing after that.
And really, it would be hard to know how well we were doing.
So what we did is we took four cultural values, four values that we believe if we commit to these four values,
it will help us produce our mission and our vision.
It's kind of shrinking things down to the smallest common denominator.
These four values, we believe if we actually get these right, that we will be able to move forward in our mission and our vision.
So number one, my favorite, I'll be honest with you, this is my favorite.
All of them are great.
This is my favorite.
We unite for the sake of the gospel.
In order to remain focused on successfully creating a Christ-centered community that cultivates God's kingdom on earth above all else,
we hold secondary theology with an open hand.
Because the gospel is so important, we hold secondary theology with an open hand.
We unite for the sake of the gospel.
A Christ-centered community is only possible when we are laying down our preferences
to prioritize the gospel above everything else.
The reality is unity is at the heart of Christ's vision for his church.
In John 13, he says,
They will know you are my disciples by your love for one another.
John 17, Jesus literally prays for you and me, for everyone who will follow Jesus after the disciples.
And he says, I pray that they will be one just as you and I are one if I'm honest.
As a pastor in the American church, I don't think we're great at prioritizing unity.
We get in intellectual arguments over secondary theology.
We get in intellectual arguments over our preferences of how we like to worship or the ministry philosophy that we prefer.
And at the end of the day, we've got to prioritize unity for the sake of the gospel.
The gospel is too important for us to get distracted by arguments with one another.
Look, this is my favorite.
And the reality is it's coming from somebody who loves theology.
I spent years of my life and a lot of my parents' money studying theology.
But what I've realized over the past 10 years is that if studying theology does not transform you into a person of love,
who seeks common ground with a diverse group of brothers and sisters in Christ, then it's all a waste.
Some of the most unkind interactions I've had with people are people who are intellectually sure of their secondary theology.
Paul says this in 2 Timothy,
"Don't have anything to do with foolish and stupid arguments, because you know they produce quarrels.
And the Lord's servant must not be quarrelsome, but be kind to everyone, able to teach, not resentful.
Opponents must be gently instructed in the hope that God will grant them repentance,
leading them to a knowledge of truth.
Not saying that secondary theology isn't important or good.
Pursue the knowledge of the Scriptures, but do it in a way that produces humility and unity and kindness.
Please study the Bible. Form educated opinions. I have my own.
But at the end of the day, we have to hold them with an open hand and a charitable spirit towards those we disagree with.
The one thing, the one thing I have little patience for is people who become convinced of their systematic theology without charity.
They often ignore that there are godly people who are smarter than them on the other side,
who love the Scriptures, who love Jesus and have a different interpretation.
So in summary, the message of Jesus is good news to the poor.
It opens the eyes of the blind. It sets captives free.
It's far too important for you or me to let our preferred biblical interpretations or styles of worship get in the way.
There is one body of Christ.
So we intentionally lay down our preferences to unite for the sake of the gospel.
This has to be a mark of our church.
If we're going to be about cultivating the kingdom of God, we got to unify around what matters most and and lay aside our opinions on secondary things.
Our next value is this. We rely on the living and written word of God.
I talked about this at the beginning, although we have some autonomy in defining our unique mission, vision and values as a church.
Ultimately, all of this is guided by one thing and one thing only: the word of God.
We don't get to make up what we think is important in our culture.
The Scriptures and the life of Jesus and the teachings of Jesus tell us what should be our top priority.
2 Timothy 3 says that all Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable.
John 1:14 says that Jesus, the word, became flesh and dwelt among us.
At the end of the day, the decisions we make as a church and the direction we head as a church
is defined by what the Scriptures clearly teach and what is reiterated by the life and teachings of Jesus.
We are, will, and always will be. How did I? I messed that up.
We were, are, and will always be a Bible-trusting, Jesus-centered church.
The way I like to envision this with the Scriptures and Jesus being the living word, the Scriptures being the written word,
is that the Scriptures are our dartboard and the life and teachings of Jesus are our bullseye.
Matt said this last week. He said that for him, the Sermon on the Mount is the canon within the canon.
It's the central focus of the life and teachings of Jesus.
And so we, we hone in on what's most important and the further out on the dartboard we get, the more open handed we are about those things.
So does our life reflect a total reliance on and obedience to what is clearly taught in the Scriptures
and reiterate it by the life and teachings of Jesus?
Is our church totally reliant on and obedience to what's taught in Scriptures and reiterate it in the life and teachings of Jesus?
Or do we pick and choose ideas from Scripture and Jesus that we like and ignore the parts that we don't?
May we never ignore the hard truths of Scripture.
May we be a church that totally relies on the written and living word of God.
Okay, number three, we prioritize real relationships.
I already spent a lot of time on this in our mission statement.
So I'm not going to beat a dead horse.
I'll just say this, church is not an event we attend.
It is a community that we engage in.
You were never intended to follow Jesus alone.
You cannot grow in your faith in isolation or without authentic vulnerability.
You have to be willing to be honest with yourself and those around you as we pursue Jesus together.
James chapter five says it this way.
Is anyone among you in trouble?
Let them pray.
Is anyone happy?
Let them sing songs of praise.
Is anyone among you sick?
Let them call on the leaders, the elders of the church to pray over them and anoint them with oil in the name of the Lord.
And the prayer offered in faith will make the sick person well.
The Lord will raise them up.
If they have sinned, they will be forgiven.
Therefore, confess your sins to each other and pray for each other so that you may be healed.
The prayer of a righteous person is powerful and effective.
If we want to be a healthy, vibrant church, we have to intentionally pursue authentic and honest relationships with one another.
Are you investing in authentic relationships aimed at being informed to the image of Jesus?
Am I investing in authentic relationships aimed at being informed to the image of Jesus?
Are you just showing up and consuming or are you plugging in and investing?
We prioritize real relationships.
Lastly, we cultivate spiritual gifts to serve others.
Church is primarily about giving of yourself for the good of the community.
Every follower of Jesus has spiritual gifts, talents, and callings that serve the whole.
The American church tends to view the church through the consumer lens.
We want to fight back against this temptation by cultivating our gifts to serve others.
First Corinthians talks about it.
I was going to read it.
I don't have time.
It gives this illustration of the body that every part of the body matters.
Each one of you has something to offer to this church.
No gift is more valuable than any other gift.
Every part matters.
When we refuse to cultivate our gifts, the whole body misses out.
A church is healthiest when all of the believers at that church understand their gifts
and use them in accordance with the overall vision of the church.
So do you know your gifts?
Do you understand who God has made you to be?
What he's calling you to do?
Are you using your gifts to cultivate the kingdom of God inside and outside the church?
If not, let's talk.
I'd love to help you figure this out.
This is what I'm passionate about.
I'm passionate about equipping saints to do the work of the ministry.
Let me help you figure out what God's calling you to do.
Okay, so in conclusion, as we think about this common direction that we've laid out as a church,
this is where we want to go as a church.
We want to invite real people with real lives into a Christ-centered community.
We want to cultivate the kingdom of God on earth by obeying Jesus clearly and proclaiming Jesus boldly.
I might have flipped those around.
And we unite for the sake of the gospel.
We rely on the living and written word of God.
We prioritize real relationships and we cultivate our gifts to serve others.
This is where we're headed.
This is where we want to go.
My question for you is, is this something that you can get excited about?
Because we want our church to be excited about our mission, our vision, and our values.
If not, let me help you find a church that you can get excited about.
Because again, we're all about cultivating the kingdom of God.
I'm okay if you would prefer to go somewhere else.
Again, we're not building our brand here.
If this is something you can get excited about, man, let's journey together.
Imagine what God can do through our church over the next few years if we stay committed to this mission together.
Last week, as Matt ended his sermon, he asked us to ponder this question.
Where do we want to go in our relationship with God in 2024?
I was sitting at my in-law's house in their living room and as he asked me to ponder that question,
I was trying to get in a spot where I could just meditate on the question and think about what God wants for me
and ask the Holy Spirit to give me wisdom.
And there was a Christmas tree in the corner of the room and they had a star at the top of the Christmas tree.
That was like flickering lights glimmering at the top of the tree.
And I just thought, okay, so that's where I'm headed with God.
I'm headed towards Jesus, conformed to the image of Jesus, focused on that.
And then below the star were all kinds of things that could distract me from keeping my gaze on the star.
There was red lights, green lights, blue lights, ornaments, family pictures, all kinds of things.
And I just, I felt the Holy Spirit say, keep your eye focused on the star.
Keep your eye focused on the primary thing.
Pursue Jesus.
Be conformed to the image of Jesus in 2024.
Don't get distracted by things that might be good, might be bad, might be neutral.
It doesn't matter. Keep your eyes focused on the star.
What I shared this morning is our church's north star.
It's where we are headed.
Let's focus on this together and let's be unwilling to be distracted by anything else.
There will be plenty of things, plenty of opportunities, plenty of exciting things that are going to cause us as a church to look away from the thing that we've decided we want to do.
My primary job as the pastor and your secondary job as invested members is to stay focused on this mission, vision and values.
Call each other out when you see us stepping out of line.
Our call as a church is too important to get distracted or to coast along.
Together, let's vigilantly commit to this direction.
Let's stay focused on creating a Christ-centered community that we can invite our friends, neighbors, co-workers and even our enemies to.
So that the kingdom of God can be cultivated in the city of Winchester as it is in heaven.
Let's pray.
Father, I am so grateful for your word, for the wisdom and direction it gives to our lives.
I'm so thankful for Jesus, who is the word made flesh, dwelt among us, who showed us exactly how to live.
Sacrificial enemy love, kindness, humility, patience and righteous anger towards the religious.
God, may we be a people who pursue Jesus together.
God, may you supernaturally create a Christ-centered community here at our church that can be used to cultivate the kingdom of God through proclaiming Jesus clearly and obeying Jesus boldly.
God, may we take serious unity in the church.
May we lay down our preferences in order to prioritize the gospel.
May we be authentic and honest with one another about our struggles.
May we ask for prayer, for healing.
May we weep with those who weep.
Rejoice with those who rejoice.
God, may we understand the gifts that you've given us.
May we use those to serve your church.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Thank you.
Bye.